“ဓားတောင်” တွင်အဓိက ဇာတ်ဆောင် လေးဦးသာ ပါပါသည်။
ဇာတ်ဆောင် လေးဦးတို့ အနက် တစ်ဦးမှာ အလုပ်သမားသံချောင်း၊
နောက်တစ်ဦးမှာ အိမ်ပြေး ရဲမြင့်၊
နောက်တစ်ဦးမှာ ကဗျာဆရာ ယောင်ယောင်
ဘာယောင်ယောင်ဖြင့် အလုပ်လက်မဲ့ဖြစ်နေသော ပညာတတ် ကိုနန္ဒာ
မှောင်ခို စက်လှေ ပိုင်ရှင် ဦးဘရန်တို့ဖြစ်ပါသည်
သူတို့လေးဦးသည် သင်္ဘောပျက်ပြီး ကျွန်းကလေး တစ်ကျွန်းပေါ်သို့
ရောက်သွားသည့်အခါတွင် လူ့အဖွဲ့အစည်းကလေးတစ်ခုကို ထူထောင်ခဲ့ကြပါသည်
သံချောင်းတို့သည်လက်တွေ့ကျသူ ဖြစ်ပါသည်
ဘ၀အခက်အခဲတို့ကို ရင်ဆိုင်ရဲသူဖြစ်ပါသည်။
ကိုနန္ဒာသည် စာတွေ့ကို သိထားသူဖြစ်ပါသည်
ရဲမြင့်သည် လမ်းမှားသို့ရောက်နေရာမှ သံချောင်းကိုကြည့်ပြီး
ဦးဘရန်သည် ရောက်လေရာရာတွင် ကိုယ်ကျိုး ကြည့်သူ
နောက်တစ်ဦးမှာ ကဗျာဆရာ ယောင်ယောင်
ကိုနန္ဒာသည် စာတွေ့ကို သိထားသူဖြစ်ပါသည်
သံချောင်းတို့သည်လက်တွေ့ကျသူ ဖြစ်ပါသည်
နောက်တစ်ဦးမှာ ကဗျာဆရာ ယောင်ယောင်
“ဓားတောင်” တွင်အဓိက ဇာတ်ဆောင် လေးဦးသာ ပါပါသည်။
And Y is a dependency of class X.
Class X may have many dependencies,
and class Y may also have many dependencies.
This is desirable, as it allows
functionality to be reused throughout
the application. without duplicating code.
Classes that use other classes are said to be coupled.
And these dependencies can be
either loosely or tightly coupled.
Let's have a look at some code
that demonstrates tighty coupled classes.
Here are two classes, the product service class,
the generation EAN 13 barcode for a product.
This class depends on the EAN 13 barcode class.
Now when a product service class is created,
the constructor must be passed an instance
of the EAN 13 barcode class,
and only the EAN 13 barcode class can be passed.
The product service is dependent on this barcode class.
This is an example of a tightly coupled class.
As no other class, other than this specific
EAN 13 barcode class can be used to create a product.
It is said that the product service class is tightly coupled
to the EAN 13 barcode class.
This is considered undesirable, as it means
the only barcode that the product service
can generate for a product is type EAN 13.
So, what if later on we need to generate
an EAN 8 or an EAN 5 barcode
or some other type of barcode. This design, we cannot.
Tightly coupled classes reduce code reuse.
Which is an important tenant
of object orientated programming.
And aides development, code readability, and code standards.
As developers, we should strive for
loosely coupled designs between objects.
So what does a loosely coupled
relationship between classes look like.
A way to loosen coupling is via interfaces.
So the product service class could be made to depend
on the code generator interface, rather than
the concrete EAN 13 barcode class.
Let's have a look at this in code.
As you can see the product service is dependent
on the code generator interface.
And we have three implementations of that interface.
EAN 5 barcode,
EAN 8 barcode,
and EAN 13 barcode.
Now, when the product service is instantiated,
any one of the three code generator implementations
can be passed to the constructor.
You can see that in action in the bootstrap class.
Where I have created a product service three times.
Each time with a different code generator implementation.
And if I run the code, you can clearly see,
that a different EAN is generated for each product service.
This way of achieving loose coupling is perfectly acceptable
but, we can do better.
And this is where dependency injection comes in.